A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller photographs, Photo Files, RG 1 FA1128
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Public Relations File, 1954 - 1990; 13
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S., 1961-1990; 1
    - Rockefeller, Laurance S.: MSKCC: CBS Photos, 1973; Black and white 8x10 prints and duplicates. (Box 73, Folder 1076)
      PR photo no. 2.11. LSR at MSKCC, with doctors, viewing building models. Photos from Gene Garry of CBS, taken during filmed visit to MSKCC. Also includes one photo of LSR golfing at Mauna Kea.
    - MSKCC: LSR and Staff, 1977; Black and white 8x10 (Box 73, Folder 1077)
      PR photo no. 2.12. Two photos taken for 1977 MSKCC Annual Report. LSR and 4 staff members (taken in Lewis Thomas's office).
    - New York State Office of Parks and Recreation (Sal J. Prezioso, commissioner), 1970 July 24; Black and white 8x10, with captions. (Box 73, Folder 1078)
      PR photo no. 2.13. Swearing in of Sal J. Prezioso as Commissioner of Parks and Recreation. Includes LSR and NAR.
    - MSKCC: New Construction, Undated; Black and white, 8x10 (Box 73, Folder 1079)
      PR photo no. 2.14. LSR and group observing construction site.
    - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation (Henry Diamond, commissioner), 1970 June 25; Three black and white 8x10 prints. (Box 73, Folder 1080)
      PR photo no. 2.15. Swearing in of Henry Diamond as state commissioner of Environmental Conservation, June 25, 1970. Includes LSR, NAR, and Robert Moses. Photos by Bob Wands.
    - Rockland Lake State Park, 1969 July 3; 4 color 8x10 prints. (Box 73, Folder 1081)
      PR photo no. 2.17. Portraits of LSR at Rockland Lake State Park. Four shots of LSR in rowboat (alongside aquatic plants), below cliffs, at picnic table (photo used on cover of Robin Winks' book). Photos taken by Look magazine. Prints dated January 1970. (See slides in 2.73.)
    - New York Zoological Society Meeting, 1970; 8x10 black and white print (Box 73, Folder 1082)
      PR photo no. 2.18. Photo of LSR with Mayor John Lindsey.
    - Rockland Lake State Park (Look, November 4, 1969), 1969 July 3; Color 8x10 print (7 copies) (Box 73, Folder 1083)
      PR photo no. 2.19. LSR standing on shore of Rockland Lake. Photo used in Look magazine, November 4, 1969 issue.
    - Rockland Lake State Park (Look,November 4, 1969), 1969 July 3; Black and white 8x10 print. (Box 73, Folder 1084)
      PR photo no. 2.20. LSR standing on shore of Rockland Lake. Photo used in Look magazine, November 4, 1969 issue.
    - New York State Council of Parks and Outdoor Recreation Meeting, 1969 August 11; Black and white 8x10 prints. (Box 73, Folder 1085)
      PR photo no. 2.21. LSR, Robert Moses, and regional commissioners at Council of Parks meeting, Jones Beach State Park. Exhibit and cake cutting for 40th anniversary of Jones Beach State Park.
    - State Park Commission for the City of New York, 1968 January; Black and white 8x10 print. (Box 73, Folder 1086)
      PR photo no. 2.22. LSR, S. J. Schulman, and Fred Smith viewing plans for proposed Bronx State Park site (Roberto Clemente State Park). Press release announcing appointment of Schulman as general manager of State Parks Commission for the City of NY, January 30, 1968.
    - Conference on Scenic Roads, 1967 December; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 73, Folder 1087)
      PR photo no. 2.23. LSR, Sal J. Prezioso, and Edmund N. Bacon reviewing papers. No other identification of conference.
    - National Recreation and Park Association, 1967 June; Black and white 8x10 prints. Two shots with duplicate copy of each. (Box 73, Folder 1088)
      PR photo no. 2.24. Appointment of Sal J. Prezioso as executive vice president of NRPA, June 22, 1967. LSR (immediate past president), Conrad Wirth, Prezioso, and George B. Hartzog Jr.
    - New York State Council of Parks Meeting, 1967 May 15; 8x10 black and white print (6 copies). (Box 73, Folder 1089)
      PR photo no. 2.25. LSR and A. K. Morgan, chief engineer and general manager, Palisades Interstate Park Commission, shown discussing plans for North Development (bathhouse and pool) of Rockland Lake State Park. Photo taken at the NYS Council of Parks meeting, Bear Mountain, May 15; published in the Bergen Record, May 16, 1967.
    - Citizens Advisory Committee on Recreation and Natural Beauty, Joint Meeting with Society for a More Beautiful National Capital, 1967 February 16; 4 black and white prints (and negative), and 10 color prints, all 8x10. (Box 73, Folder 1090)
      PR photo no. 2.26. LSR speaking at the White House, February 16, 1967. Multiple copies and black and white negative. See also oversized folder (box O 36). Note: Correspondence in file moved from file number 2.72.
    - New York State Council of Parks Meeting, 1966 May 26; 7x9 black and white print (Box 73, Folder 1091)
      PR photo no. 2.27. LSR, S. J. Schulman, and Fred Smith viewing plans for proposed Roberto Clemente State Park. Photo taken at a State Council of Parks meeting.
    - Governor's Conference on Natural Beauty (New York), 1966 February 25; Black and white 8x10 prints with captions (Box 73, Folder 1092)
      PR photo no. 2.28. LSR speaking as a member of the Hudson River Valley Panel. Also includes photos of panel on Air Pollution, and view of delegates in audience. Photos by Ted Kell, New York Herald Tribune.
    - Johnson, Lady Bird, Vist to Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1965 September; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 73, Folder 1093)
      PR photo no. 2.29. LSR and MFR greet Lady Bird Johnson and Lynda Johnson at airport at Jackson Hole; coming for national conference of garden clubs. Photo printed in New York Post, September 8, 1965,
    - National Recreation and Park Association, 1965 August 16; Black and white 8x10 prints. (Box 73, Folder 1094)
      PR photo no. 2.30. LSR signing NRPA charter. With Conrad Wirth and others. Photos by Paul Parker.
    - White House Conference on Natural Beauty, 1965 May 25; Black and white 7x9 print. (Box 73, Folder 1095)
      PR photo no. 2.31. LSR reporting to President Johnson on White House Conference on Natural Beauty, East Room of White House, May 25, 1965. Washington Post photograph, May 20 (26?), 1965
    - Wilm, Harold G., NYS Conservation Commissioner, 1965 May 14; Black and white 8x10 print. (Box 73, Folder 1096)
      PR photo no. 2.32. LSR and NAR with Harold G. Wilm, commissioner of NYS Department of Conservation, with map of state parks entitled "?It will develop 27 state parks." (Possibly relating to a bond issue?) File dated May 14, 1965, but occasion not identified, and no documentation for date.
    - Hudson River Valley Commission, 1965 April 14; Black and white 8x10 print with caption sheet (2 copies). (Box 73, Folder 1097)
      PR photo no. 2.33. LSR, chair of the Hudson River Valley Commission, pointing to map while speaking at Press Conference on Hudson River, April 14, 1965. UPI photo.
    - MSKCC Medallion Award to Alfred P. Sloan Jr., 1965 May 18; Black and white 8x10 print, with crop marks. (Box 73, Folder 1098)
      PR photo no. 2.34. LSR presenting first MSKCC Medallion Award to Alfred P. Sloan Jr. File includes Fourfront (MSKCC publication), 8:10, Summer 1965, with article on the event and photo reproduction.
    - White House Conference on Natural Beauty, 1965 March 12; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 73, Folder 1099)
      PR photo no. 2.35. Photo of LSR with LBJ and others on White House porch. LSR met with Lyndon Baines Johnson at the White House, March 12, 1965; file includes White House Press Release announcing plans for the Conference to be held May 24-25, 1965.
    - United Neighborhood Houses Award, 1975 June 3; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 73, Folder 1100)
      PR photo no. 2.36. LSR and MFR at United Neighborhood Houses Award dinner, honoring the Rockefeller Family and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, June 2, 1975, Pierre Hotel, New York. Photo from Women's Wear Daily, June 5, 1975.
    - Palisades Interstate Park Commission: Fort Lee Historic Park, 1964 November 21; 8x10 black and white prints. (Box 73, Folder 1101)
      PR photo no. 2.37. LSR, as vice president of the Palisades Interstate Park Commission, speaking at ceremonies at Fort Lee Bluff. Includes photo of Continental army reenactors. Includes PIPC press release, November 23, 1964, concerning the cermonies and plans to acquire the property as an historical site
    - Theodore Roosevelt Association Award, 1963 October 27; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 73, Folder 1102)
      PR photo no. 2.39. LSR receiving Theodore Roosevelt Association Distinguished Service Medal, as NAR looks on. Presented by Lyman Tondel.
    - New York State Council of Parks, 1963 January 17; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 73, Folder 1103)
      PR photo no. 2.40. LSR on his election as chairman of the New York State Council of Parks, January 17, 1963. Photo by Newsday
    - Conservation Service Award (U.S. Department of the Interior), 1962 May 25; Black and white 8x10 print. (Box 73, Folder 1104)
      PR photo no. 2.41. LSR receiving award plaque from Stewart Udall, secretary of the Interior, at White House Conference on Conservation, May 25, 1962. NPS photo. Photo inscribed "For Laurance - Who won it many times over! Stewart." Includes covering note from Udall.
    - Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, 1962 January 31; Black and white 8x10 prints. Multiple copies. (Box 73, Folder 1105)
      PR photo no. 2.42. LSR, as chairman, presenting ORRRC report Outdoor Recreation for America to President John F. Kennedy, January 31, 1962, at the White House. MFR and other ORRRC members. Includes two contact sheets. At least some photos by UPI. Multiple shots; some cropped prints.
    - Spelman College and Atlanta University Center, 1961 May 11; 8x10 black and white prints. (Box 73, Folder 1106)
      PR photo no. 2.43. LSR, as president of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, presenting RBF grant of one million dollars to Spelman College and Atlanta University Center. Accepted by Dr. Albert E. Manley, president of Spelman College. Photos by Wide World Photos. (3 shots)
    - "Wings Club Photo of LSR", Undated; 5x7 color prints (3 copies). (Box 73, Folder 1107)
      PR photo no. 2.46. Photo of LSR standing outdoors in Jackson Hole, Wyoming (winding camera). No date or other explanation of Wings Club attribution.
    - MSKCC, Undated; 8x10 black and white prints. (Box 73, Folder 1108)
      PR photo no. 2.49. LSR and others in hard hats on construction site (for MSKCC). No dating or identification provided.
    - Conservation: Adirondacks Trip, 1965 October 10-11; 8x10 black and white prints, with captions. (2 shots plus duplicate copies) (Box 73, Folder 1109)
      PR photo no. 2.67. LSR and NAR on Adirondacks pack trip, with William Petty, District Director of Lands and Forests for the Conservation Department, and with Conservation Commissioner Harold Wilm. UPI photos. (Image of LSR and NAR on horseback cropped from photo with Petty.)
    - MSKCC: Dedication of New Hospital Building, 1973 November 13-14; Black and white 8x10 prints (Box 73, Folder 1110)
      PR photo no. 2.72. LSR speaking at podium, in large tent, at MSKCC Dedication of New Hospital, 1973 November 13-14. (File mislabeled as LSR speaking before Citizens Advisory Committee on Natural Beauty and Recreation, Joint Meeting with Society for a More Beautiful National Capital, February 16, 1967 (for which, see 2.26). Correspondence from file 2.72 moved to file 2.26.) Plus two shots moved to this file from file 2.49.
    - Rockland Lake State Park, 1969 July 3; Color slides. (Box 73, Folder 1111)
      PR photo no. 2.73. Six color slides of LSR at Rockland Lake State Park. Photos taken by Look magazine. One photo used in Look, November 4, 1969 issue. File includes correspondence concerning the slides, 1970-1981. (See also prints in 2.17, 2.19 - 2.20.)
    - MSKCC: Cox, Patricia (Tricia) Nixon (Mrs. Edward), 1973 November 13-14; Black and white 8x10 (Box 73, Folder 1112)
      PR photo no. 2.75. LSR shaking hands with Tricia Nixon Cox, on occasion of dedication of New Hospital building at MSKCC. (Lewis Thomas and Benno Schmidt also in file). Photo by Guy Gillette. (See also file 2.72)
    - Marks, Paul A., M.D., 1981; Color 3.5x3.5 print (4 copies) and negative. (Box 73, Folder 1113)
      PR photo no. 2.79. LSR and Paul A. Marks (MSKCC). Prints dated June 1981.
    - Rockefeller University / MSKCC: Scholars' Residence, 1985 June 21; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 73, Folder 1114)
      PR photo no. 2.81. Groundbreaking ceremonies for New Scholars' Residence Program, 500 E. 73rd Street, NY, NY, at Rockefeller University and Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center. LSR, DR, Joshua Lederberg, Paul Marks, Benno Schmidt; in hardhats on construction site. NYT photo
    - Whitney Museum, 1981 October 30; Black and white 8x10, and newspaper article. (Box 73, Folder 1115)
      PR photo no. 2.83. LSR and MFR at Whitney Museum Exhibition opening, October 28, 1981. Photo in Women's Wear Daily, October 30, 1981, by John Bright. MFR wearing long black dress.
    - U. S. O. Luncheon, 1986 April; Black and white 8x10 prints. (Box 73, Folder 1116)
      PR photo no. 2.86. LSR, MFR, Brooke Shields at U.S. O. Luncheon (3 shots). Also includes George Lamb, Robert H. B. Baldwin.
    - Thayer, Jeanne, and Richard Halverson, 1987; 5x7 black and white print glued to 8x11 mat board. (Box 73, Folder 1117)
      LSR with Jeanne Thayer and Richard Halverson, holding framed painting of "Cottage at (illegible)." Possibly related to Historic Hudson Valley. Written on bottom "Chairman's Report HHV 1987." Unnumbered PR photo.
    - Rockefeller, Laurance S.: Portrait (for U.S. Congressional Gold Medal), 1990 June; Black and white 8x10 print. (Box 73, Folder 1118)
      Profile head shot of LSR, used for modeling his U.S. Congressional Gold Medal. Unnumbered PR photo.
  - Rockefeller, Mary French, 1954-1988; 2
    - Rockefeller, Mary French: Portraits (Bradford Bachrach), Undated; 8x10 black and white (Box 74, Folder 1119)
      PR photo no. 2A.5. MFR wearing double strand of pearls. Square neck dress with white inset around neck. Envelope marked "Not for distribution." 29 copies.
    - World Mercy Fund Dinner: Primum Vivere Award., 1981 September 25; Black and white 8x10 print (Box 74, Folder 1120)
      PR photo no. 2A.6. MFR receiving framed award from Bishop Donal J. Murray of Nigeria and Father Thomas A. Rooney of Alexandria, VA, president of the World Mercy Fund. Dinner held at Waldorf Astoria Hotel. Includes some correspondence.
    - Portraits (Bradford Bachrach), 1973 April; Black and white 5x7 prints (Box 74, Folder 1121)
      PR photo no. 2A.7. Portrait of MFR (head and shoulders).
    - Portraits: U. S. O. Program (Bachrach), 1985 May; Black and white 8x10 prints. (Box 74, Folder 1122)
      PR photo no. 2A.10. Portrait photo taken in 1973 (same outfit as in 2A.7, slight difference in pose and finish). Bachrach attribution not on front of photo. (File also contains correspondence concerning LSR and MFR gift to YWCA's Fund for the Future, May 1985. Indicates that Karsh photo was used for the Fund for the Future bulletin (not found in file).)
    - U. S. O. Woman of the Year Luncheon, 1985 May 16; Black and white matte 8x10 prints (Box 74, Folder 1123)
      PR photo no. 2A.11. MFR speaking. Nice photos of MFR and LSR together at luncheon and at podium. Held at Palace Hotel, New York, NY. Photos (3 shots) by D'Arlene Studio.
    - Portraits (Bachrach), 1973; 8x10 black and white print (Box 74, Folder 1124)
      PR photo no. 2A.13. Same outfit and pose as in 2A.10 portrait by Bachrach. Slight difference in finish. Note attached to photo reads: "Do not use."
    - Portraits, 1988 December; Black and white 8x10 print (4 copies) (Box 74, Folder 1125)
      PR photo no. 2A.15. Portrait of MFR (head and shoulders) wearing single strand of pearls and dress with gathered yoke detail. Bachrach portrait taken December 1988.
    - Hitchcock, Elizabeth French, 1954, 1973; Black and white 8x10-5x7 prints. (Box 74, Folder 1126)
      1954 portrait of Elizabeth French Hitchcock by Pach Brothers, NY. 1973 photo of Mary French Rockefeller, Elizabeth French Hitchcock, and two other women at YWCA event. Unnumbered PR photo, removed from no. 2A.5.
  - General, 3
    - Grand Teton National Park, Undated; Black and white 8x10 prints (Box 74, Folder 1127)
      PR photos - General 5. Three views of cabins, Jackson Lake Lodge from above, river bend and mountains.
    - Woodstock, VT: Mansion, Undated; Black and white 8x10 print (4 copies) (Box 74, Folder 1128)
      PR photos - General 20. View of Mansion from front.